MANISHA

MEAN / MERN / Full Stack / AWS Serverless / Devops A Full-Stack consultant with extensive proven experiences related to software development, currently working as a Tech Lead. For the last few years, my forte has been Javascript. I follow agile methodologies and best practices to bring the ideas into life from scratch and to scale it up on Cloud. I am a Docker, CI/CD, and Serverless enthusiast. I always believe in perfecting my craft and so making strides to learn everything that I can about development.

PERSONAL INFO

7992480960

https://manishamuskan.github.io/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/manishamuskan/

EXPERIENCES IN BRIEF

Practice Agile Development Methodology

Analyze Project / Business Requirements

Design Solution with Best Practices in Mind

Work with Serverless Architecture (AWS)

Project Deployment with CI/CD Integration(AWS)

Build and Manage Team

Take Ownership of End-to-End Project

Help with UI/UX and Restful APIs

Achieve 80%-90% Test Coverage

Create Reusable Modules

On-Time Delivery of Projects

Demo / Presentation to Clients

NEW INTERESTS

Blockchain

ML / AI / IoT

CoFounded - NESTAGEN

SOFT SKILLS

Self-Motivated

Self-Disciplined

Curios and Adaptable

Team Player

Organized

Optimistic and Humble

HANDS ON EXPERIENCES

UI/UX Designing Html 5 | CSS3 / SCSS | Bootstrap / Materialize CSS |

Media query | Photoshop (CS3)

Development Angular 6+ | Angular JS | React JS (+ redux) | Ionic |

Node JS | ES 6/7 | TS | PHP (Laravel / CakePhp) | .Net

(C#) | MVC | Java (Basics) | Android (Basics)

Code Coverage Mocha | Karma | Jest | Assertion Libraries

Databases MongoDB | SQL Server | My SQL

Deployment / Devops / AWS Serverless (IAM, Lamda, S3, Route53, DynamoDb,

EC2, EBS, Cognito) | Cloud Native | Docker |

Kubernetes | Jenkins | Travis CI | JIRA | Git Flow |

Nginx / Apache Server

CAREER SUMMARY

Delivery Centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

Others

Served as **Sr. MEAN** stack developer, later on promoted to **Tech lead**. **Designed the product solution** and managed the development teams.

Whyable Technologies Pvt

Ltd, Bangalore

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018

Served as **Sr. software developer**, responsible for **end-to-end delivery of the projects**. Was also introduced to **microservices architecture** during project development.

Ubique IT Solutions Pvt Ltd. Ranchi

chi

Served as **Lead Webdeveloper**, mentored junior UI/UX developers in the team and trained interns.

Oct 2016 - Mar 2018

iCordinate Pvt Ltd, Hydrabad

Sept 2014 - mid 2016

Served under a remote contract position as a **Web Developer**, learnt concepts and ensured deliverable milestones were met.

EDUCATION

2017 Masters in Computer Application

IGNOU, Ranchi

2013 Bachelors in Computer Application

Ranchi University (St. Xavier's College)

PROJECTS SUMMARY

CRYPTO - AUTO TRADER (Current project – Node Application)

Delivery centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Jul 2019 - *

Project Requirement

The project requirement was to make a console application to automate the trading (buy / sell) of Cryptocurrencies based on market insights and certain strategies. This is an inhouse Project to make profits using current stock assets as well as to keep a maintained in/outflow, stock of crypto supply for the CryptoCentric Project

Approaches and Achievements

Worked and successfully lead a the project

Automated login to the different third Parties such as Binance, Bittrex & Zerodha Intelligent Pricing module to optimize profits

Creating triggers based on Strategies

Creating webhooks based on custom Email client and Triggering a trade based on it

CRYPTOCENTRIC (Last Project - Web Application)

Delivery centric Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Oct 2018 - Jul 2019

Project Requirement

The requirement was to build a secure *Crypto Currency Exchange* similar to an e-commerce platform that deals with the buy and sells of crypto currencies such as Bitcoin, Ether, and other digital coins for the Australian Market. A similar project CoinCentric already existed but was not as reliable, secure & modular as per the current needs, and was developed using MULESOFT, OIM, OAM, Oracle DB and .Net and few other traditional technologies.

Approach Followed

Breaking down the requirements into independent modules keeping **Micro-services** in mind.

Architecting a **cloud based solution** from scratch using **MEAN** as tech stack.

Used **JIRA** to keep track of project modules progress & **Docker** for containerization.

Used **JWT Token** to implement **role and session based authorization** / **authentication**.

Integrated third party services such as **POLI payments**, **SMS**, **Google Services** etc.

Development of modules like **OTP module**, **KYC Verification module**, **Payment and Transaction module** etc.

Deployment on **AWS EBS** and Use of **Bit-bucket** and **Jenkins** to achieve **CI/CD**. Setting up **load balancer** to handle more requests.

Achievements

30% Faster Turn Around in Development

A much more enhanced Security

Monolithic to **Micro-services with scale on demand** in mind, running on cloud Cut the Product cost by 40% using Open Source Technologies.

ODE SYSTEMS (Hybrid Application)

Whyable Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bangalore

Jul mid 2018 - Sep 2019

Brief Project Description

ODE Systems was regarding the development of **chart based hybrid application** that helps the user to make a decision out of two or more choices based on the criterion created by the user himself. Followed **MEAN Stack** approach along with **lonic** Framework. Created **API solutions** and **Reusable components** in angular. Used **PouchDB** to **sync the application state** online as well as offline. I also created **plug and play UI utility example code page (UI Sink)** for internal team by using HTML/SCSS only so that the UI utilities can be reused anywhere regardless of framework or library. Deployed on **App Store & Play Store**.

INVISIBLE CITY (Hybrid Application)

Whyable Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

Brief Project Description

The project was about making an emotions based solution where users can register and can give feedback about the place they have visited, very similar to Google places app but for the Australian population only. The whole purpose of the project was to keep track of people's emotions tagged to a particular place that is supposed to be used by the research and development team of the client's University for the Australian population. Technologies used to develop this project are **lonic**, **NodeJs**, **Express Js and MongoDB and D3 JS charting library** to create an overlapping chart. **Location Clustering** was used to avoid location collision. We used **S3 buckets** to store the image files uploaded by the user. I integrated **Social login** feature for the project and created admin panel. As tools, I used **Android Studio** and **Xcode** to build the application for android and IOS mobile platform respectively. I also deployed the applications in their respective marketplaces. I deployed the project in **AWS (EC2 instance)** also implemented **CI/CD** for this project.

FILE IDS

Brief Project Description

Ubique IT Solutions Pvt Ltd, Ranchi

Dec mid 2017 - Mar 2018

This project was developed in many phases. In that development cycle, the requirement was to make the process of filing IDS hassle-free. The application requires some patent-related details and auto-fill the rest of the form by consuming EPO's data (**OPS web services**). I used .**Net(C#)** with **Jquery** to develop the complete solution, Integrated **OAuth 2.0 Authentication** with **AJAX** requests to consume the APIs.

VANITY 360 (Web Application)

iCoordinate Pvt. Ltd., Hydrabad

Feb 2016 - Oct 2016

Brief Project Description

The Project was about developing an e-commerce Website from scratch. It also included creating Admin panels with different roles and functionalities. I used the design prototype provided by UX designer and created the **Pixel Perfect Responsive UI** for both customers as well as the admin end from scratch. Considered **mobile-first approach** during entire UI development process. I was introduced to **Restful APIs** as backend and **angular JS framework** for front-end development.